<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs Page on Thiruvannamalai Arunachaleswarar Temple – History &amp; Significance</title>
    <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs Page on Thiruvannamalai Arunachaleswarar Temple – History &amp; Significance</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indra Lingam (East)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/indra-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/indra-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indra-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Indra Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indra Lingam is situated on the eastern side of the Arunachaleswarar Temple in Thiruvannamalai, along Karu Street. It is the first Lingam encountered on the sacred Girivalam (circumambulation) path. On Pournami (Full Moon) days, devotees begin their Girivalam by offering prayers at this Lingam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the East direction and is associated with the Taurus (Rishabha) and Libra (Tula) zodiac signs. Indra, the King of the Devas (Celestial Beings), is believed to have consecrated this Lingam. Worshipping here is believed to bestow good health, mental strength, fame, and leadership qualities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni Lingam (Southeast)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/agni-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/agni-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;agni-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Agni Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Agni Lingam is located on the southeastern stretch of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Seshadri Ashram and Lotus Tank. This is the second Lingam encountered during the Girivalam (circumambulation) and is uniquely positioned on the right-hand side of the path—unlike the others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Southeast direction and is associated with Leo (Simha) zodiac sign. It was consecrated by Agni, the Fire God and one of the Pancha Bhootas. Devotees believe that worshipping at this Lingam bestows purification, strength, health, and vitality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esanya Lingam (Northeast) </title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/esanya-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/esanya-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esanya-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Esanya Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Esanya Lingam is located on the northeastern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Esanya Mutt, close to the junction of the temple and Ramana Ashram Road. It is the eighth and final Lingam encountered during the sacred Girivalam (circumambulation) of Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Northeast direction, considered highly auspicious and spiritually charged. It is associated with the Sagittarius (Dhanus) and Pisces (Meena) zodiac signs. The Lingam was consecrated by Esanya, the guardian of the Northeast and the embodiment of spiritual wisdom and divine knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubera Lingam (North)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/kubera-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/kubera-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kubera-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Kubera Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kubera Lingam is located on the northern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Raja Gopuram (main temple tower). It is the seventh Lingam encountered during the sacred circumambulation of the Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the North direction and is associated with the Virgo (Kanya) and Pisces (Meena) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Kubera, the Lord of Wealth and Guardian of the North. Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bless devotees with material prosperity, spiritual abundance, and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Niruthi Lingam (Southwest)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/niruthi-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/niruthi-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;niruthi-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Niruthi Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Niruthi Lingam is located on the southwestern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai. It is the fourth Lingam encountered during the sacred circumambulation. This Lingam lies in a quieter stretch of the path and is revered for its deep, protective energy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Southwest direction and is associated with the Pisces (Meena) and Sagittarius (Dhanus) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Niruthi, the guardian deity of the Southwest, often linked with protection and karmic purification. Devotees believe that praying here helps remove ancestral curses, negative energies, and grants fame and childbirth blessings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Varuna Lingam (West)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/varuna-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/varuna-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;varuna-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Varuna Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Varuna Lingam is situated on the western side of the sacred Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the town&amp;rsquo;s drainage canal. It is the fifth Lingam encountered by devotees performing the holy circumambulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the West direction and is associated with the Cancer (Kataka) and Capricorn (Makara) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Varuna, the Vedic God of Water, Rain, and Cosmic Order. Worshipping here is believed to grant mental peace, emotional balance, health, and control over the senses and speech.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vayu Lingam (Northwest)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/vayu-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/vayu-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vayu-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Vayu Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vayu Lingam is located on the northwestern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the intersection of the Girivalam route and the Vayu Theertham (sacred water source). It is the sixth Lingam encountered during the divine circumambulation of the Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Northwest direction and is associated with the Gemini (Mithuna) and Aquarius (Kumbha) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Vayu, the God of Wind and Life Force (Prana). Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bring long life, health, mental clarity, and spiritual progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yama (Ema) Lingam (South)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/yama-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/thiru-asta-lingam/yama-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yama-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Yama Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Yama Lingam is located on the southern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the cremation grounds and along Chengam Road. This is the third Lingam encountered during the sacred Girivalam journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the South direction and is associated with the Aries (Mesha) and Scorpio (Vrischika) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Yama, the Lord of Death and Dharma. Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bestow protection from untimely death, longevity, righteous living, and release from fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
