<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybamatica on Hubstream</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybamatica on Hubstream</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indra Lingam (East)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/indra-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/indra-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indra-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Indra Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Indra Lingam is situated on the eastern side of the Arunachaleswarar Temple in Thiruvannamalai, along Karu Street. It is the first Lingam encountered on the sacred Girivalam (circumambulation) path. On Pournami (Full Moon) days, devotees begin their Girivalam by offering prayers at this Lingam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the East direction and is associated with the Taurus (Rishabha) and Libra (Tula) zodiac signs. Indra, the King of the Devas (Celestial Beings), is believed to have consecrated this Lingam. Worshipping here is believed to bestow good health, mental strength, fame, and leadership qualities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni Lingam (Southeast)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/historical-hindu-temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/historical-hindu-temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;introduction-to-annamalaiyar-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Annamalaiyar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple (Tamil: அண்ணாமலையார் திருக்கோவில்) is a very old and famous temple for Lord Shiva and Goddess Parvati. It is located at the base of Annamalai Hills in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu, India. This temple is one of the most important Shiva temples in Tamil Nadu. It represents the fire element (Agni) among the five natural elements called Pancha Bhoota Sthalams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;main-deities--lord-annamalaiyar-and-goddess-unnamulai&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Deities – Lord Annamalaiyar and Goddess Unnamulai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main god of this temple is Annamalaiyar (Tamil: அண்ணாமலையார்), a form of Lord Shiva, who is believed to be one with the Annamalai Hill. His wife is Unnamulai Ammai (Tamil: உண்ணாமுலை அம்மை), a form of Goddess Parvati.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni Lingam (Southeast)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/agni-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/agni-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;agni-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Agni Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Agni Lingam is located on the southeastern stretch of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Seshadri Ashram and Lotus Tank. This is the second Lingam encountered during the Girivalam (circumambulation) and is uniquely positioned on the right-hand side of the path—unlike the others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Southeast direction and is associated with Leo (Simha) zodiac sign. It was consecrated by Agni, the Fire God and one of the Pancha Bhootas. Devotees believe that worshipping at this Lingam bestows purification, strength, health, and vitality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture, Shrines, Halls</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;complex-and-towers&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex and towers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple is located at the base of the Annamalai Hills and faces east. The entire temple complex spreads across 25 acres of land. The outer walls measure about 700 feet (210 meters) on the east and west sides, 1,479 feet (451 meters) on the south side, and 1,590 feet (480 meters) on the north side. The present-day stone structures and towers are believed to have been built in the 9th century CE, as confirmed by inscriptions from the Chozha kings who ruled during that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esanya Lingam (Northeast) </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/esanya-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/esanya-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esanya-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Esanya Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Esanya Lingam is located on the northeastern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Esanya Mutt, close to the junction of the temple and Ramana Ashram Road. It is the eighth and final Lingam encountered during the sacred Girivalam (circumambulation) of Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Northeast direction, considered highly auspicious and spiritually charged. It is associated with the Sagittarius (Dhanus) and Pisces (Meena) zodiac signs. The Lingam was consecrated by Esanya, the guardian of the Northeast and the embodiment of spiritual wisdom and divine knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;early-devotional-records-by-saint-poets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Devotional Records by Saint-Poets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 7th century CE, the great Shaivite saints Sambandar and Appar, known as the Nayanmars, praised Annamalaiyar Temple in their devotional hymns called Thevaram.&#xA;Sekkizhar, the famous poet of the Periyapuranam, also wrote that both Sambandar and Appar visited and worshipped Lord Annamalaiyar at this temple. In later times, the temple was also known as the Arunachalesvara Temple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;patronage-by-the-chozha-dynasty&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patronage by the Chozha Dynasty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The powerful Chozha kings ruled this region from around 850 CE to 1280 CE. They were great supporters of this temple.&#xA;Inscriptions from their rule mention many gifts given to the temple, such as land, cows, sheep, and oil, often offered in celebration of their victories and devotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/swamy.songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/swamy.songs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;நமச்சிவாய&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;திருச்சிற்றம்பலம்!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;தொல்லை இரும்பிறவிச் சூழும் தளை நீக்கி&#xA;அல்லல் அறுத் தானந்தம் ஆக்கியதே - எல்லை&#xA;மருவா நெறியளிக்கும் வாதவூர் எங்கோன்&#xA;திருவாசகம் என்னும் தேன்.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(திருப்பெருந்துறையில் அருளியது தற்சிறப்புப் பாயிரம்)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;நமச்சிவாய வாஅழ்க நாதன்தாள் வாழ்க&#xA;இமைப்பொழுதும் என்நெஞ்சில் நீங்காதான் தாள்வாழ்க&#xA;கோகழி யாண்ட குருமணிதன் தாள்வாழ்க&#xA;ஆகம மாகிநின் றண்ணிப்பான் தாள்வாழ்க&#xA;ஏகன் அநேகன் இறைவ னடிவாழ்க&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;வேகங் கெடுத்தாண்ட வேந்தனடி வெல்க&#xA;பிறப்பறுக்கும் பிஞ்ஞகன்றன் பெய்கழல்கள் வெல்க&#xA;புறத்தார்க்குச் சேயோன்றன் பூங்கழல்கள் வெல்க&#xA;கரங்குவிவார் உள்மகிழுங் கோன்கழல்கள் வெல்க&#xA;சிரங்குவிவார் ஓங்குவிக்குஞ் சீரோன் கழல்வெல்க&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ஈச னடிபோற்றி எந்தை யடிபோற்றி&#xA;தேச னடிபோற்றி சிவன்சே வடிபோற்றி&#xA;நேயத்தே நின்ற நிமல னடிபோற்றி&#xA;மாயப் பிறப்பறுக்கும் மன்ன னடிபோற்றி&#xA;சீரார் பெருந்துறைநம் தேவ னடிபோற்றி&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubera Lingam (North)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/kubera-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/kubera-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kubera-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Kubera Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kubera Lingam is located on the northern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the Raja Gopuram (main temple tower). It is the seventh Lingam encountered during the sacred circumambulation of the Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the North direction and is associated with the Virgo (Kanya) and Pisces (Meena) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Kubera, the Lord of Wealth and Guardian of the North. Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bless devotees with material prosperity, spiritual abundance, and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legend</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/legend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/legend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-divine-test-by-lord-shiva&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Divine Test by Lord Shiva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once, a disagreement arose between Lord Brahma and Lord Vishnu. Each one believed that he was greater than the other. To teach them the truth and guide them, Lord Shiva appeared as a huge pillar of endless fire, called the Jyoti Sthambha (Pillar of Light).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;brahma-and-vishnu-begin-the-search&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brahma and Vishnu Begin the Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To decide who was supreme, Shiva said: &amp;ldquo;Whoever finds the top or the bottom of this fire pillar will be the greatest.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Brahma took the form of a swan and flew up to find the top.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Vishnu became a boar (Varaha) and dug deep into the earth to find the base.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Niruthi Lingam (Southwest)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/niruthi-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/niruthi-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;niruthi-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Niruthi Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Niruthi Lingam is located on the southwestern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai. It is the fourth Lingam encountered during the sacred circumambulation. This Lingam lies in a quieter stretch of the path and is revered for its deep, protective energy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Southwest direction and is associated with the Pisces (Meena) and Sagittarius (Dhanus) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Niruthi, the guardian deity of the Southwest, often linked with protection and karmic purification. Devotees believe that praying here helps remove ancestral curses, negative energies, and grants fame and childbirth blessings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religious significance, Saints and literary mention</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/religious-and-saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/religious-and-saints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;religious-significance&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Religious significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple is one of the Pancha Bhootha Sthalams, which are five holy temples of Lord Shiva, where He is worshipped in the form of the five natural elements:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earth&lt;/strong&gt;: Kanchipuram (&lt;strong&gt;Ekambareswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Water&lt;/strong&gt;: Kalahasti (&lt;strong&gt;Kalahasteeswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Fire&lt;/strong&gt;: Tiruvannamalai (&lt;strong&gt;Annamalaiyar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Air&lt;/strong&gt;: Tiruvanaikaval (&lt;strong&gt;Jambukeswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Space&lt;/strong&gt;: Chidambaram (&lt;strong&gt;Nataraja Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this temple, Shiva appeared as a huge column of fire, known as Akkini Jothi. Even the powerful gods Brahma and Vishnu could not find the top or bottom of this divine flame, showing that Shiva is beyond measurement or limit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Varuna Lingam (West)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/varuna-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/varuna-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;varuna-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Varuna Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Varuna Lingam is situated on the western side of the sacred Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the town&amp;rsquo;s drainage canal. It is the fifth Lingam encountered by devotees performing the holy circumambulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the West direction and is associated with the Cancer (Kataka) and Capricorn (Makara) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Varuna, the Vedic God of Water, Rain, and Cosmic Order. Worshipping here is believed to grant mental peace, emotional balance, health, and control over the senses and speech.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vayu Lingam (Northwest)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/vayu-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/vayu-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vayu-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Vayu Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vayu Lingam is located on the northwestern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the intersection of the Girivalam route and the Vayu Theertham (sacred water source). It is the sixth Lingam encountered during the divine circumambulation of the Arunachala Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the Northwest direction and is associated with the Gemini (Mithuna) and Aquarius (Kumbha) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Vayu, the God of Wind and Life Force (Prana). Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bring long life, health, mental clarity, and spiritual progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worship and Festivals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/workship-and-festivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/workship-and-festivals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;grand-festivals--thiruvizha&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grand Festivals – Thiruvizha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The temple celebrates many festivals every year. The four most important ones are called Thiruvizha (grand festivals).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest festival is held during the Tamil month of Karthikai (November–December). It lasts for ten days and ends with the Karthigai Deepam celebration. On this special day, a huge lamp is lit on top of Annamalai Hill, using over three tons of ghee in a large cauldron. This sacred flame is visible from miles away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yama (Ema) Lingam (South)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/yama-lingam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thiru-asta-lingam/yama-lingam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yama-lingam--location&#34;&gt;Yama Lingam – Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Yama Lingam is located on the southern side of the Girivalam path in Thiruvannamalai, near the cremation grounds and along Chengam Road. This is the third Lingam encountered during the sacred Girivalam journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Lingam represents the South direction and is associated with the Aries (Mesha) and Scorpio (Vrischika) zodiac signs. It was consecrated by Yama, the Lord of Death and Dharma. Worshipping at this Lingam is believed to bestow protection from untimely death, longevity, righteous living, and release from fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Us Page</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us Page</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/contactus/contactus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/contactus/contactus/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post -test</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/solutions/chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/solutions/chatbot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resorces Page</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/resources/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/resources/resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools Page</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/tools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
