<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Page test 2 on Thiruvannamalai Arunachaleswarar Temple – History &amp; Significance</title>
    <link>//localhost:56072/temple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Page test 2 on Thiruvannamalai Arunachaleswarar Temple – History &amp; Significance</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:56072/temple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agni Lingam (Southeast)</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/historical-hindu-temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/historical-hindu-temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;introduction-to-annamalaiyar-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Annamalaiyar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple (Tamil: அண்ணாமலையார் திருக்கோவில்) is a very old and famous temple for Lord Shiva and Goddess Parvati. It is located at the base of Annamalai Hills in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu, India. This temple is one of the most important Shiva temples in Tamil Nadu. It represents the fire element (Agni) among the five natural elements called Pancha Bhoota Sthalams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;main-deities--lord-annamalaiyar-and-goddess-unnamulai&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Deities – Lord Annamalaiyar and Goddess Unnamulai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main god of this temple is Annamalaiyar (Tamil: அண்ணாமலையார்), a form of Lord Shiva, who is believed to be one with the Annamalai Hill. His wife is Unnamulai Ammai (Tamil: உண்ணாமுலை அம்மை), a form of Goddess Parvati.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture, Shrines, Halls</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;complex-and-towers&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex and towers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple is located at the base of the Annamalai Hills and faces east. The entire temple complex spreads across 25 acres of land. The outer walls measure about 700 feet (210 meters) on the east and west sides, 1,479 feet (451 meters) on the south side, and 1,590 feet (480 meters) on the north side. The present-day stone structures and towers are believed to have been built in the 9th century CE, as confirmed by inscriptions from the Chozha kings who ruled during that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;early-devotional-records-by-saint-poets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Devotional Records by Saint-Poets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 7th century CE, the great Shaivite saints Sambandar and Appar, known as the Nayanmars, praised Annamalaiyar Temple in their devotional hymns called Thevaram.&#xA;Sekkizhar, the famous poet of the Periyapuranam, also wrote that both Sambandar and Appar visited and worshipped Lord Annamalaiyar at this temple. In later times, the temple was also known as the Arunachalesvara Temple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;patronage-by-the-chozha-dynasty&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patronage by the Chozha Dynasty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The powerful Chozha kings ruled this region from around 850 CE to 1280 CE. They were great supporters of this temple.&#xA;Inscriptions from their rule mention many gifts given to the temple, such as land, cows, sheep, and oil, often offered in celebration of their victories and devotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legend</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/legend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/legend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-divine-test-by-lord-shiva&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Divine Test by Lord Shiva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once, a disagreement arose between Lord Brahma and Lord Vishnu. Each one believed that he was greater than the other. To teach them the truth and guide them, Lord Shiva appeared as a huge pillar of endless fire, called the Jyoti Sthambha (Pillar of Light).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;brahma-and-vishnu-begin-the-search&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brahma and Vishnu Begin the Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To decide who was supreme, Shiva said: &amp;ldquo;Whoever finds the top or the bottom of this fire pillar will be the greatest.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Brahma took the form of a swan and flew up to find the top.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Vishnu became a boar (Varaha) and dug deep into the earth to find the base.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religious significance, Saints and literary mention</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/religious-and-saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/religious-and-saints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;religious-significance&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Religious significance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annamalaiyar Temple is one of the Pancha Bhootha Sthalams, which are five holy temples of Lord Shiva, where He is worshipped in the form of the five natural elements:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earth&lt;/strong&gt;: Kanchipuram (&lt;strong&gt;Ekambareswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Water&lt;/strong&gt;: Kalahasti (&lt;strong&gt;Kalahasteeswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Fire&lt;/strong&gt;: Tiruvannamalai (&lt;strong&gt;Annamalaiyar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Air&lt;/strong&gt;: Tiruvanaikaval (&lt;strong&gt;Jambukeswarar Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Space&lt;/strong&gt;: Chidambaram (&lt;strong&gt;Nataraja Temple&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this temple, Shiva appeared as a huge column of fire, known as Akkini Jothi. Even the powerful gods Brahma and Vishnu could not find the top or bottom of this divine flame, showing that Shiva is beyond measurement or limit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worship and Festivals</title>
      <link>//localhost:56072/temple/workship-and-festivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:56072/temple/workship-and-festivals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;grand-festivals--thiruvizha&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grand Festivals – Thiruvizha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The temple celebrates many festivals every year. The four most important ones are called Thiruvizha (grand festivals).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest festival is held during the Tamil month of Karthikai (November–December). It lasts for ten days and ends with the Karthigai Deepam celebration. On this special day, a huge lamp is lit on top of Annamalai Hill, using over three tons of ghee in a large cauldron. This sacred flame is visible from miles away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
